Wyck Association Collection 1663-1972 Mss.Ms.Coll.52
American Philosophical Society
Wyck Association Collection
1663-1972
Mss.Ms.Coll.52
American Philosophical Society
151.5 Linear feet
One of the oldest houses in Philadelphia, Wyck is now a non-profit museum listed on the National Register of Historic Places. Nine generations of the Jansen-Wistar-Haines family owned the Wyck property from 1690 until 1973. The last family owner deeded 2.5 acres of land, the house and its contents, several outbuildings, a landscaped garden, and a small endowment to the Wyck Charitable Trust. The Wyck Charitable Trust and the Wyck Association now administer the preservation of the property and its educational services to the public. This collection contains diaries, letters, accounts, bills and receipts, deeds, and photographs. The collection as a whole is deepest for the period 1770-1970. Items of particular note include accounts of household expenses at Wyck from ca. 1790-1970; papers pertaining to the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, Quaker schools, and social reform groups; agricultural and horticultural practices; and correspondence to and from cultural leaders of 18th and 19th century Philadelphia. The papers of the John S. Haines family (Ms. Coll. 52A) form part of the Wyck Papers. The papers cover the years 1845 to 1949 and are arranged into eight series.
Wyck Association.
African American History Note
With emphases on religion, education, and social concerns, the correspondence in the Wyck collection contains numerous references to African Americans. These issues emerge in the correspondence of Caspar Wistar Haines I, Hannah Marshall Haines, Reuben Haines III, Jane Bowne Haines I, Robert Bowne Haines I, and Caspar Wistar Haines II.See below for more specific subject references within the letters.
The collection also contains a series of writings: diaries, essays, journals, notebooks, and poetry. Of particular interest are the papers describing the exploits of a runaway slave, Henry Hudson, in 1819.
Early American History Note
The Wyck Collection is a massive collection that touches upon a number of early American themes. MOLE contains an extensive inventory of the collection. There are also binders with the collection that contain item level descriptions of the contents. The collection is particularly notable for its family correspondence, business records, and information on the operations of some Philadelphia institutions, such as the Academy of Natural Sciences.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
On deposit from the Wyck Association and the Wyck Charitable Trust, 1987, 1988.
Scope and Contents note
The Wyck Papers are a vast and important archive documenting one of Philadelphia's most historic homes over the course of three centuries.
The collection is organized into ten series arranged by type of material. Selected portions of Series II, III, IV, and V are available on microfilm at Wyck House, the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, and the Library of Congress.
Series I. Genealogy 2.25 lin. feet
Series II. Correspondence 1676-1971 31 lin. feet
Series III. Writings 1721-1970 14.75 lin. feet
Series IV. Financial materials 1746-1972 33.25 lin. feet
Series V. Estate materials 1693-1967 11 lin. feet
Series VI. Legal materials 1684-1944 3.25 lin. feet
Series VII. Memorabilia 1663-1961 6.5 lin. feet
Series VIII. Subject file n.d. 10 lin. feet
Series IX. Pictorial material 1761-1958 5.5 lin. feet
Series X. Oversized materials 25 boxes
Biographical/Historical note
One of the oldest houses in Philadelphia, Wyck was inhabited by nine generations of the Jansen, Wistar, and Haines families from, the 1680s until 1973. The last owners deeded 2.5 acres of land, the house and its contents, several outbuildings, a landscaped garden, and a small endowment to the Wyck Charitable Trust. The Wyck Charitable Trust and the Wyck Association now administer the preservation of the property and its educational services to the public.
Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia.; Haines family; Haines, Ann, 1793-1869; Haines, Caspar Wistar, 1762-1801; Haines, Caspar Wistar, 1853-1935; Haines, Hannah Marshall, 1765-1828; Haines, Jane B., 1869-1937; Haines, Jane Bowne, 1790-1843; Haines, Jane Reuben, 1832-1911; Haines, John Smith, 1820-1886; Haines, Margaret Vaux Wistar, 1831-1917; Haines, Margaret Wistar, 1728-1793; Haines, Mary T., 1892-; Haines, Reuben, 1727-1793; Haines, Reuben, 1786-1831; Haines, Robert B., 1827-1895; Haines, Robert B., 1893-1967; Hartshorne, Catherine Haines, 1761-1809; Jansen family; Wistar family; Wyck House (Philadelphia, Pa.); Abolition, emancipation, freedom; Accounts.; Agriculture; Bills (financial).; Business and Skilled Trades; Business Records and Accounts; Culture, community, organizations; Deeds; Diaries.; Early National Politics; Family Correspondence; Home economics--United States--Accounting; Horticulture; Institutional Records; Literature, Arts, and Culture; Marriage and Family Life; Miscellaneous; Pennsylvania History; Philadelphia (Pa.)--Social life and customs; Philadelphia History; Photoprints; Quakers; Race, race relations, racism; Receipts; Reconstruction; Religion, religious organizations; Science and Technology; Slaves, slavery, slave trade; Social conditions, social advocacy, social reform; Social problems.; Trade
- Series I. Genealogy, 2.25 Linear feet 6 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Starting in the early nineteenth century, residents of Wyck collected genealogical information about their ancestors, particularly in regard to the Bowne, Haines, and Wistar families. Included in the collection is genealogical research done by Reuben Haines III primarily on the Haines family in the first decades of the nineteenth century. Later in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries, Jane Reuben Haines, Caspar Wistar Haines II, Jane Bowne Haines II, and Reuben Cope Haines conducted extensive research on the three previously mentioned families as well as on more distant relations in the Hartshorne, Johnson, Lukens, Marshall, and other families. Further genealogical information may be found in the correspondence of Reuben Haines III, Jane Reuben Haines, Caspar Wistar Haines II, Jane Bowne Haines II, and Reuben Cope Haines.
  The material in this section is arranged alphabetically by family surname. The dates in the listings have two meanings. Dates enclosed in parentheses and marked "b." and "d." refer to the life span of the person immediately preceding the dates, for example, "Caspar Wistar (b.1672 d.1726)." All other dates refer to the time periods included in the material, for example, "Eliza Beth Bowne's descendants, 1773-1903."
  - Armitt (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ashton (Asheton) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bacon (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Badcock, Barton, Bowman (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bowne (Incl. biographical information by Reuben Cope Haines), c.1595. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bowne Notebook incl. biographical information re. John Bowne (b.1629-d.1695) (Box 1, Folder 6 bound bk)
  - Bowne incl. "comparison of Lists in the Bowne Family" and "Lists of Bowne Connections" (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bowne re. Robert Bowne and Elizabeth Hartshorne Bowne's descendants, 1773-1902 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bowne re. Thomas Bowne's (b.1595) descendants (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bowne re Thomas Bowne's (b.1595) descendants arranged by R. H. III (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bowne re. Feake Family, 1609-1903 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bowne Misc. notes (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brown (e) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Burr incl. notebook re. Burr, Matlock, Collins, Smith, Cooper, et. al. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Carpenter (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Castner, Coat (es) (Cote) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Collins (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cooper, Cope, Dillworth (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dinsdale, Garrigues, Grimes (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Frith incl. biographical material, and coat of arms (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Haines Misc. ancestral charts re. RBH III, MIH, CWH II, et. al. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Haines re. Bacon, John S. Haines, RBH I, Stewardson, and Warder families (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Haines re. CWH I, RH III, JSH, RBH I; Incl. biographical information, 1762-1895 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Haines re. Cooper, Marshall and Shoemaker families, c. 1700 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Haines re. D. Jansen Haines, Emlyn Stewardson, Marion Haines Emlen, Elizabeth Haines Kimber (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Haines re. Haines family, et. al.; "Ancestry of the Haines, Sharp, Collins, families," book by George Haines M.D. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Haines "Genealogical Notes" re. Haines et al. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Haines re. HMH, JBH I, et.al, incl. extracts from correspondence (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "In the Beginning God" by William L. Haines, c.449 - 1920 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Haines re. John (I), Jonathon, Nehemiah, Joseph Haines, et al., 1684-1830 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Haines Misc. information (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Haines Misc. information re. Haines et al. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Haines Misc. notes (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Haines Misc. notes (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Haines "The Name and Family of Haynes or Haines" by Media Research Bureau (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Haines Notebook re. Haines family et al. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Haines Notebook re. Haines et al., collected by Reuben Cope Haines (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Haines (Heynes) "Pedigree of Heynes" collected by RH III, by JBH II, 1914, 1935 incl. coat of arms 617-1607, 1816 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Haines re. Richard Haines by RH III, 1810 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Haines re. Richard Haines' descendants, 1682 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Haines re. Richard Haines' descendants, 1682 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Haines re. Richard Haines; "Memoir of Richard Haines," book by Charles R. Haines, 1633-1685 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Haines re. Richard, John, Josiah, and Reuben Haines; incl. biographical information, 1682-1793 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Haines re. RBH II, WJH, Isabelle P. Haines; incl. biographical information, 1857. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    General note
    Obit. Mary T. Haines
  - Hardiman (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Hartshorne Book 1 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Hartshorne Book 2 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Hartshorne Collected by RBH I (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Hartshorne Collected by Reuben Cope Haines (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Hartshorne Collected by Reuben Cope Haines (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Hartshorne "Hartshornes in America" (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Hartshorne re. Hartshornes in Monmouth, Middletown, and Philadelphia (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Hartshorne re. Richard Hartshorne's descendants (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Hartshorne re. William and Thomas Hartshorne; also account of storm at sea (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Hearne, Heath (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Hill, Hudson (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Jansen (Johnson) (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Jones (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Keppele, Klincken, Kripner (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Kunders, Landis (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Lisle (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Lukens (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Marshall; Christopher Marshall's descendants (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Marshall Historical and biographical material re. Marshall family (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Marshall Misc. notes (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Marshall re. Sarah Lyn and Sarah Thompson Marshall's ancestors (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Milan re. Hans Milan's descendants; also Mylin, Meylin, et al. (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Morris, Nedro, Nixon (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Pennock "The Pennocks of Primitive Hall" (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Pole (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Preston (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Salter (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Sharpless, Shoemaker, Shotwell (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Stewardson (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Streypers, Thomlinson, Turner (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Underhill (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Ustick (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Van Aken (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Vaux (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Walm (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Warder (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Willis (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Wistar ancestor charts re. ancestors of Rebecca Morris, Clarence Wyatt Bispham (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Wistar re. Caspar Wistar (b. 1696-d. 1752) notes by CWH I (?) and JBH II (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Wistar re. Caspar Wistar (b. 1696-d. 1752) incl. pamphlet and genealogies re. CW's descendants (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Wistar re. Caspar Wistar M.D. (b. 1801-d. 1867) card catalogue of CW's descendants (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - Wistar re. Caspar Wistar M.D. (b. 1801-d. 1867) CW's descendants (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Wistar re. Hans Caspar Wistar's (b. 1672-d. 1726) descendants (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Wistar Misc. notes (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Wistar Notebook incl. biographical information re. Caspar Wistar (b. 1696-d. 1752) et al. (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - Wistar re. Thomas Wistar's (b. 1764-d. 1851) descendants (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Wistar "The Wistar Family" re descendants of Caspar Wistar (b. 1696-d. 1752) (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Woolrich (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Miscellaneous Material re. Genealogy (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Oversized
    - Bowne re. Thomas Bowne's descendants, 1595-1806 (Box OS6, Folder 28)
    - Haines "Ancestral Tables" ancestors of RBH I, c. 1600-1827 (Box OS6, Folder 29)
    - Haines form Griffin ap Beli to grandchildren of Reuben Haines III 617-1900 (Box OS6, Folder 30)
    - Haines - Richard Haines' descendants, 1682 (Box OS6, Folder 31)
    - Hartshorne re. Thomas Hartshorn's descendants, 1715 (Box OS6, Folder 32)
    - Descendants of John and Elizabeth Haynes, South Carolina, 1700-1795 (Box OS6, Folder 33)
    - Wistar (er) Re: Caspar Wistar's descendants, 1696-1752 (Box OS6, Folder 34)
    - Wister, John; chart of descendants, 1727-1927 (Box OS21, Folder 140)
    - Wistar, Caspar and Katharine; family tree (Box OS21, Folder 142)
- Series II. Correspondence, 1676-1971; 31.0 Linear feet 80 boxes
  The correspondence, dating from 1676-1971, is the most extensive series in the Wyck Papers. It includes the letters of family members, as well as correspondence to and from notable people as listed in this Register. The correspondence particularly illustrates the internal development of this family, the development of American thought and society, and the relationship between family and society. The emphases on religion, education, and concern for Blacks are topics which exemplify this dynamic. These issues emerge in the correspondence of Caspar Wistar Haines I, Hannah Marshall Haines, Reuben Haines III, Jane Bowne Haines I, Robert Bowne Haines I, and Caspar Wistar Haines II.
  The Correspondence is arranged by the principal family member to whom it relates. These grouping of letters start with the correspondence of Reuben Haines I (1727-1793) and end with that of Mary Troth Haines (1892-). The separate groupings of letters are divided further into correspondence "from" the individual and "to" the individual. Each of these subdivisions is arranged in chronological order. The complete list of family members represented in the Papers follows the Introduction, on pages 3 and 4.
  Family correspondence is, by its nature, interlocked. It is recommended, then, that researchers consider the papers of an individual as a part of a network of papers that includes those of his/her parents, siblings, spouses, and children. Research on the Correspondence of Reuben Haines I, for example, would not be complete without at least a cursory examination of the Correspondence of his wife, Margaret W. Haines, or their children, Caspar Wistar Haines, Reuben Haines II, Josiah Haines, or Catherine (Haines) Hartshorne. The Genealogy charts of the family found at the beginning of the Register will be useful for establishing the relationships between the various generations represented in the Papers.
  The Correspondence has been arranged to focus upon those family members who owned and/or resided at Wyck. These individuals are indicated by an asterisk on the list of family members on pages 3 and 4. The Wyck Papers include an unusual number of letters written by these family members. These letters contain richly autobiographical statements about the writer and his/her world. In order to maximize the autobiographical quality of the Correspondence the letters of asterisked family members have been arranged in "From" and "To" categories. For example, the letters associated with Reuben Haines III are divided into "Correspondence from Reuben Haines III" and "Correspondence To Reuben Haines III." The letters are arranged chronologically within each of these two categories.
  In the common case of intrafamily mail of Wyck residents the writer, rather than the receiver, was favored. For example, a letter from Reuben Haines III to his wife Jane B. Haines was filed chronologically within the "Correspondence From Reuben Haines III." Conversely, a letter from Jane B. Haines to her husband would be found in the "Correspondence From Jane B. Haines I."
  Correspondence of those family members who did not live at Wyck (non-asterisked) was placed, when possible, in the correspondence of asterisked family members. For example, letters from William J. Haines, a non-resident of Wyck, to his brother Caspar W. Haines II, a resident of Wyck, were placed in "Correspondence To Caspar W. Haines II."
  Letters among family members who did not live at Wyck (non-asterisked) were placed in the collection of the person who received the letter. For example, a letter from William J. Haines to his sister Mary M. Haines may be found in the "Correspondence To Mary M. Haines." Letters from family members to non-family members were placed in the "From" collection of that family member.
  Following the family correspondence are all non-family letters arranged alphabetically by receiver. The alphabetical list of names appears at the end of these notes. Letters not associated with a family member include a collection of correspondence from Anthony Morris to his children from 1790 to 1816.
  Duplicate letters and duplicate copy books are noted at the end of the Register for the Correspondence. The list of Oversize copy books filed in the Oversize Materials follows that of the duplicate letters.
  The Register notes individual letters that are unusual and significant by merit of the subject matter or the persons mentioned in the body of the letter.
  - From: Reuben Haines I
    - Morris Birkbeck; Samuel Wallis, 1783 June 3- 1792 Nov. 26 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - To: Reuben Haines I
    - Samuel Wallis, 1766 Nov. 4- 1773 Aug. 27 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Cadwallader Colden; Samuel Wallis; R. L. Hooper, 1774 Aug. 10- 1775 June (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Samuel Wallis; Morris Birkbeck, 1777 Aug. 22- 1795 May 9; 3 folders (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
      - Folder 4, 1777 Aug. 22- 1786 Dec. 4 (Box 7)
      - Folder 5, 1787 Feb. 16- 1795 Mar. 29 (Box 7)
      - Folder 6, 1795 May 9 (Box 7)
  - From: Margaret Wistar Haines
    - David Rittenhouse, 1774 Jan. 6- 1789 Jul. 4 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Anthony Morris; Indians; yellow fever epidemic, 1793 Jan. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Yearly Meeting of Women Friends (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - n.d. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - To: Margaret Wistar Haines
    - Morris Birkbeck, 1756 Aug. 25- 1783 Oct. 22 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Jane Watson, 1791 Feb. 2- 1793 Aug. 9 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - From: Richard Hartshorne
    - estate of CWH I, 1801 Jan. 29- 1810 Dec. 8 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - estate of RH III, 1830 Feb. 6- 1836 Sep. 11 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - To: Richard Hartshorne
    - 1803 May 23- 1809 Oct. 20 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - James P. Parke; John F. Watson, 1810 Jul. 5- 1815 Nov. 20 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - 1821 Feb. 15- 1824 June 7 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - From: Caspar Wistar Haines I
    - 1783 Sep. 26- 1789 Jul. 15 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - William Savery; religious mission; Joseph Richardson, Jane Watson, 1790 Apr. 27- 1790 Aug. 30 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - religious mission, 1790? (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - brewing; Josiah Matlack; Dr. Caspar Wistar; yellow fever epidemic, 1792 May 17- 1793 Sep. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - death of MWH; yellow fever epidemic; William Savery; Dr. Caspar Wistar, 1793 Oct. - 1793 Dec. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Josiah Matlack; Sarah Mansel, 1794 June 28- 1796 Jul. 19 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - education; death of child; yellow fever epidemic, 1797 Jan. 6- 1797 Dec. 18 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - John Fries' treason trial; yellow fever epidemic, 1798 Mar. 12- 1799 Dec. 29 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - fire in Philadelphia brewhouse; gardens at Westtown; locust plague, 1800 Feb. 5- 1800 Jun 17 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Samuel Wallis; death of child; Timothy Matlack, 1800 Aug. 10- 1800 Sep. 4 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Germantown turnpike; sinking of Constellation; Morris Birkbeck and land fraud suit, 1801 Jan. 15- (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - estate letterbook, 1801 Jul. 2- 1807 Feb. 3 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Anthony Morris; Lewis Mumford court case, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Samuel Wallis estate, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - To: Caspar Wistar Haines I
    - business with pirates; George Washington; brewing; Jane Watson, 1785 Mar. 5- 1790 Jul. 4 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Samuel Wallis; Jane Watson; Negroes; horses, 1790 Jul. 25- 1791 Dec. 18 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - "turnpike search"; Niagara Falls, 1792 Apr. 30- 1792 Dec. 20 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - yellow fever epidemic, 1793 Jan. 9- 1793 Oct. 15 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - moral implications of brewing; Caspar Wistar; Dutch language, 1794 Jan. 30- 1794 Oct. 19 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Josiah Matlack; Morris Birkbeck, 1795 Jan. 17- 1796 Dec. 30 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Dr. Caspar Wistar; yellow fever epidemic, 1797 Mar. 28- 1798 Oct. 10 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Josiah Matlack; Samuel Wallis, 1799 Jan. 19- 1799 Oct. 24 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - 1800 Feb.5-1800 Dec.16 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Morris Birkbeck, 1801 Apr.8-1801 Nov.2 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - CWH I estate, 1807 Jan. 9-1807 Feb.12 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - From: Catharine Haines Hartshorne
    - yellow fever epidemic; black nurses, 1790 May 14-1796 Oct.10 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - 1797 Jan.9-1797 May 29 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - slavery, 1797 Jan.6-1797 Dec.13 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Westtown School; George Washington, 1798 Feb.21-1799 Dec.29 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - 1800 Jan.26-1800 Nov.19 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - 1801 Jan.22-1802 Oct.23 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - George Fox, 1803 Jan.22-1803 Nov.25 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - "hose Company", 1804 Jan.4-1804 Nov.25 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - 1805 Feb.25 1805 Dec. 3 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - 1806 Feb.11-1806 Dec.27 (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - 1807 Jan. 6-1807 Oct.26 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - To: Catharine Haines Hartshorne
    - 1786 Jul.16-1793 Sep.12 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - From: Hannah Marshall Haines
    - 1785 Apr.13-1789 Jul. 2 (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - smallpox vaccination, 1790 Apr.23-1793 (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - Dr. Caspar Wistar; Benjamin Rush; yellow fever; garden, 1797 Jan.10-1797 May 20 (Box 12, Folder 57)
    - travel from Philadelphia from Germantown; farming, 1797 Jul.15-1797 Dec.16 (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - George Washington's death, 1799 Jun.19-1799 Dec.21 (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - Germantown Turnpike; John Johnson, 1800 Feb.22-1801 May 15 (Box 12, Folder 60)
    - solar eclipse; J. P. Parke; 4th of July celebration; trip to Flushing; hose companies, 1805 Jun.26 1805 Aut.5 (Box 12, Folder 61)
    - Strawberry Hill; Society of Friends, 1807 Jul.15-1807 Aug. 4 (Box 12, Folder 62)
    - Roberts Vaux; trip to Niagara; "Embargo"; quintuplets, 1808 Mar.25-1808 Aug.26 (Box 12, Folder 63)
    - travels to Connecticut and New York; arrest for travelling on Sunday., 1808 Aug.28-1808 Dec. 5 (Box 12, Folder 64)
    - illegitimate child of black servant; Lansdown; Shakers, 1809 Jul.17-1810 Sep.16 (Box 12, Folder 65)
    - travels in Pennsylvania and New York and New England; David Mumford; S. L. Mitchell [Mitchill], 1811 June 7-1811 Oct.28 (Box 12, Folder 66)
    - 4th of July; Society of Friends; George Washington; Benjamin Morris, 1812 Jul.9-1812 Nov. 6 (Box 12, Folder 67)
    - Society of Friends; economic depression; War of 1812, 1814 Mar.25-1814 Oct.28 (Box 12, Folder 68)